Joy Baker

# **Bobby Baker**

Microservices Engineer

Global,

+1-513-404-4499

robert.baker@x-team.com

http://bobbybakes.github.io/

English

#### **BACKGROUND**

#### **ABOUT**

A Senior Software Engineer with over 10 years of experience with 5 years experience in the development and architecture of microservices. A versatile engineer with expertise in cross-platform products, security protocols, and efficient data solutions. Accomplished in leading teams to deliver solid systems and applying best practices in software development.

### WORK EXPERIENCE

### Blockchain Hackathon -2nd Place Winner,

Jun, 2021 - Jul, 2021 16 days

IBC Challenge: Build a blockchain application that utilizes IBC, or build a novel use case for the IBC protocol.

- Built in Go, this project is designed to demonstrate the use of IBC between different zones in the Cosmos ecosystem for privacy preserving credential management.
- $\verb| o https://github.com/whalelephant/CertX| \\$

# Mobile Engineer, X-Team

Dec, 2020 - Apr, 2022 1 year 4 months

Swift / Kotlin

- Converting Android / iOS to KMM Shared Libraries.
- Fixing legacy iOS issues.
- SwiftUI development.
- Fixing legacy Android issues.

## Microservices Engineer, ETCH

Sep, 2018 - Present

Microservices Architecture / Development

• Architected and developed event based cloud solutions to provide secure APIs and real time data solutions in the transportation industry.

# Microservices Engineer, X-Team

Sep, 2018 - Oct, 2020 2 years 1 month

Go / Node Microservices Development

- Developed Microservices in Node.js and GoLang to serve low-latency streaming to platforms such as web and native devices.
- Responsible for migrating Node.js Microservices to GoLang.

#### Software Journeyman / Microservices Engineer, Pillar Technology

Oct, 2016 - Sep, 2018 1 year 10 months

#### Extreme Programming

- · Architected and developed a Big Data platform to advance data science within the automotive industry. Built with AWS and Hadoop.
- · Developed internal iOS applications for clerical tasks.
- Developed Android and Embedded devices in the automotive industry.
- · Developed a cyber security solution, using advanced analytics to aggregate and identify malicious threats and vulnerabilities.
- · Developed applications and provided agile consulting on an embedded software project in the automotive industry.

#### Senior Developer, IT Applications, Nationwide Insurance

Aug, 2014 - Oct, 2016

2 years 2 months

J2EE, customer-facing web applications

- Tech Lead / Mentor
- o Java / Spring MVC

# GIS Analyst and Software Developer, Stantec

Apr, 2012 - Aug, 2014

2 years 4 months

GIS Development and Analytical Cartography

- o Interactive Mapping Applications and Add-ons
- FEMA floodplain mapping
- Cartography

#### GIS Specialist, The Ohio Department of Natural Resources

Jan, 2008 - Apr, 2012

4 years 3 months

#### GIS Analyst

Groundwater Resource Mapping

# SKILLS

#### **Native Development**

Flutter ReactNative Android iC

# API Development

Golang Python NodeJS

#### MEAN

Mongo Express Angular 1/2 Node

### J2EE

WebSphere Java JSP Gradle Maven Groovy Spring MVC

#### Microservices

Vert.x AWS LINKERD Nginx Serverless.io

## **Big Data**

Hadoop HBASE SPARK

# Dev Ops

Jenkins AWS Docker Appcenter

### **EDUCATION**

Free Diving		
Wave3 35 meters PB		
Kayaking		
Fishing Extreme Leisure		
Hiking		
Backpacking		
Photography		
Sony Alpha		